{
    "id": "6fc65f82bdeb4ed2b6151cb909887778",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The winter session ………………………. on December 5th.",
            "description": "The simple present is sometimes used to talk about future events that are part of a time table.",
            "answers": [
                "starts",
                "would start",
                "start"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I will call you if I ……………………….. time.",
            "description": "The simple present is often used in subordinate clauses with a future meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "will have",
                "have",
                "would have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. we call the police?",
            "description": "Shall is used when asking for instructions.",
            "answers": [
                "Will",
                "Shall",
                "May"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. you make me a cup of tea?",
            "description": "Will is used to give instructions.",
            "answers": [
                "Will",
                "Shall",
                "May"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The plane ……………………….. at three o’clock.",
            "description": "Either could be used here however, the simple present is more common. ",
            "answers": [
                "arrives",
                "is arriving",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "By next January, we ………………………….. here for ten years.",
            "description": "The future perfect is used to say that something will have been completed by a certain time in the future.",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "will have been",
                "would be"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I promise I ……………………….. you this evening.",
            "description": "Will is used in promises.",
            "answers": [
                "would phone",
                "will phone",
                "phone"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Let’s have something to eat, …………………………. we?",
            "description": "We use shall in question tags after let’s.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "shall",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. a ghost?",
            "description": "The present perfect is commonly used with the expressions ever, never, already etc.",
            "answers": [
                "Did you ever see",
                "Have you ever seen",
                "Do you ever see"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… James in the morning and he said that he was quitting.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events.",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "have seen",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………… all her life in India.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to mean up to now. ",
            "answers": [
                "lived",
                "has lived",
                "lives"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}